the rogue ohio bar and the rep fitness
saber barbell two of the best options
available on the market but which one is
the king
what's up everybody it's jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video i've got the rogue ohio bar and
the rep fitness saber barbell in this
video i'm going to walk you through
everything both of these barbells have
to offer but for the sake of this video
i'm going to compare the two and help
you decide which one is best for you now
before we get this show on the road i
gotta let you know we have reviewed a
ton of barbells on barbin.com and to
learn more about our top picks just
google barbin best barbells and you can
find out for yourself which one takes
home the top spot
[Music]
okay so let's get this video started
with a few similarities that these two
barbells share this is the stainless
steel version of the rogue ohio bar it's
a beast when it comes to fighting off
rust and corrosion stainless steel is
the best quality you can ask for this is
the black zinc version of the rep
fitness saber barbell does not offer as
much protection to rust but it's still a
really good option now the knurling on
both of these barbells is more on the
moderate side which is great for
anything high frequency or high rep and
also those olympic style lifts cross fit
lifts power cleans you know whatever it
may be that's ideal and since both the
sleeves on these barbells do spin you're
gonna have more success doing those
lifts than you would with a bar that
doesn't provide as much spin on their
sleeves and a really cool thing here is
that
these bars neither one of them have a
center knurling which is even better for
those olympic style lifts it's not going
to irritate your skin too bad when it's
continuously rubbing up against it which
is an awesome feature
[Music]
all right enough about the similarities
what about the differences between these
two barbells let's start with the
knurling here the knurling on the rogue
ohio bar in my opinion is better that's
due to it being stainless steel and you
know the zinc coating probably plays a
factor in this grip on the rep saber
it's still a good grip but in my opinion
this rogue ohio bar it's just a little
bit more grippy in my opinion
when we talk about the sleeves the
sleeves on the rogue ohio it does have a
grooved pattern meaning you're gonna
hear a little bit of a zip when you load
and unload your plates but on the other
side you also have a better chance of
keeping those plates in their position
throughout your lift
and with the saber
it's smooth you're not going to hear
that noise but without those grooves you
do have a higher chance of the weighted
plates sliding down the sleeves over
that repeated usage
when we talk about tensile strength
which is really important to me
the rogue ohio bar it's rated at 190 000
psi which is pretty close to the max
threshold of 230 000 psi making it a
really good option in my opinion and on
the other side the rep saber barbell
it's rated at 150 000 psi which is still
good for entry and middle level weight
lifters but if you're one of those elite
high end power lifters weight lifters
you're going to want to opt in for this
barbell it's a beast
okay so let's go over some of the
options now when it comes to the rogue
ohio bar as i mentioned this is the
stainless steel version it's going to
cost you about 370 dollars the sleeves
are chrome but you can also get them in
stainless steel if you want but that's
going to be another 95
and once you tack on shipping you're
looking at about 530 for a barbell it's
expensive but it's very high quality
making this a great purchase now the
other options available you can get it
in a black zinc option similar to the
rep saber here and an e-coat those are
going to cost you about 300
the black oxide bar that's going to cost
you about 320 and the fully customizable
bar that's going to be 350. those
customizations you can choose coding of
your choice bushings of your choice make
those sleeves spin really whatever you
want
but at the end of the day all these all
these different options are around the
same price so in my opinion you're
better off just getting the stainless
steel version it's going to last you
longer and it's going to fight off rust
better than any of those other options
can
and the saber barbell also comes in a
few different options for you it does
come in a men's and women's size so the
15 kilogram bar does not come in this
black zinc it's a regular finish only
and it does not offer center knurling
that's going to cost you about 200
now when it comes to the 20 kilogram bar
you can choose for a regular zinc finish
that regular zinc finish you can choose
with or without a center knurling that
knurling is not going to change their
price it's still going to be about 230
dollars now this
20 kilogram version with the black zinc
coating
you do not have the choice for that
center knurling and that's going to cost
you about 260 bucks
[Music]
so as you can see the rep saber bar is
the cheaper option of the two so if
price is something that's a real big
deal for you and you have a tight budget
you might want to opt in for this
cheaper bar it's also worth noting that
rep fitness as well offers pay later
through paypal for interest free
payments that 15 kilogram bar it's gonna
run you about 50 bucks per payment the
20 kilogram bar with the regular zinc
finish does not matter if it comes with
or without that center knurling you're
looking at about around 60 bucks and
this 20 kilogram bar with the black zinc
finish that's going to cost you about 65
so either way it's gonna get broken up
if you don't want to make that big
purchase up front
okay so the build between these two
barbells are a bit different and since
there are multiple options of each
barbell those builds are also going to
vary but for the sake of this video
we're going to stick with the stainless
steel version of the rogue ohio in the
black zinc version of the rep saber
since the rogue ohio is stainless steel
it's a beast when it comes to fighting
off rust and corrosion it's gonna do
that better than this black zinc can
while the zinc is nice and it can help
with that it's just not going to compare
to this
the knurling on both i couldn't help but
notice that the rogue ohio as my hands
began to sweat over time
it still just kept that good grip and
overall i think it's just more grippy
which could be very beneficial in all
facets of your workout regimen
so there are a few similarities though
with the sleeves i'm going to talk about
now they're both 16 inches in length
which is you know about standard they
also both have bronze bushings which
allow the sleeves to spin
but once again in my time i could not
notice could not help but notice that
the rep saber just spun for longer and
easier which could be awesome when it
comes to those olympic style crossfit
style lifts
now some differences of the sleeves the
rogue ohio bar does have a grooved
pattern meaning there's a little bit of
a zip noise as you're loading and
unloading the plates but
that's there to keep your plates locked
in place at a much better rate than like
this rep saber bar can because it's
smooth it doesn't have that zip but you
might need to have some weight collars
to lock those plates in because they
will slide down the sleeves over time as
you continue to use them and when you're
choosing a barbell tensile strength is
really important so
tensile strength is essentially how much
force how much weight a barbell can
handle before it begins to bend or break
so this rogue ohio bar is rated at 190
000 psi
really making it a beast and it's up
near that high end threshold of 230 000
psi on the flip side
the rep saver it's rated rated at
000 psi
it's a good option for beginners and
those moderate level weight lifters but
if you're on the higher end of things
you're an elite level power lifter
you're going to want to opt in for this
190 000 psi
it's just sturdier and it can handle
more weight than this barbell can
okay so which barbell is the barbell for
you well really it comes down to a few
different things here let's start with
the price if you're somebody on a tight
budget i would definitely suggest going
for the rep saver it's a hundred dollars
cheaper it's still high quality and it's
just as versatile as the rogue ohio bar
plus if you're somebody who's new to
weightlifting and you might not want to
spend all that money up front on a
barbell this is a good option for you
but on the flip side if you're one of
those elite level weight lifters i was
talking about earlier i would definitely
suggest the rogue ohio since the tensile
strength rating is 190 000 psi as
opposed to the 150 000 psi you found
with the saber
it's going to be able to you're going to
load on more weight with this bar and
for a longer amount of time since the
rogue ohio bar is stainless steel and
the rep saber is made of zinc
you're going to find that the rogue ohio
bar is going to fight off that rust and
corrosion
much
better than this zinc bar can do that
for you
and so my opinion when i was working out
with both of these bars as i mentioned
earlier the spinning on both of these
sleeves while it may not be significant
enough for you i found it pretty
significant so if you're somebody who's
wanting to do those crossfit lifts
olympic style lifts all of those
i would probably suggest the rep bar
because it's going to spin a little bit
easier
but as you're working out your hands
begin to sweat a little bit i also found
that
the roga higher bar just had a better
grip overall so if you're somebody like
me
and your hands do start to sweat a
little bit i would definitely suggest
this the grip here on the rep saber it's
still good but
it just doesn't really compete in my
eyes compared to the rogue ohio bar
[Music]
all right y'all that's all i have today
for this comparison video between the
rogue ohio bar and the rep fitness saber
barbell these are two good barbells in
my opinion but if i had to decide i
would go with the rogue ohio bar
the tensile strength rating is much
higher at 190 000 psi compared to the
150 000 psi of the rep saber
the stainless steel is gonna give you
more longevity it's gonna fight off that
rust and corrosion much better than this
zinc bar can
the sleeves still spin on this bar just
like the rep saber and these grooves i
don't mind the zip noise and that's
gonna help my plates stay locked in
and while both of these do have a
moderate style grip i still found that
the stainless steel bar had a better
grip as my hands begin to sweat so if
you're somebody like me and your hands
start sweating over time
this is it right here this rogue ohio
bar is an absolute beast in the weight
room and it should be the next bar that
you purchase for your personal space
thanks for watching everybody i hope
this video was helpful as you look to
make your next barbell purchase you can
always head over to barbin.com to read
more about both of these products just
google barbin rogue ohio bar review or
barbin rep fitness saber barbell review
both of those articles are gonna pull up
and you can read into more detail over
the things we discussed today i'll see
y'all next time
[Music]
[Applause]
now